A Guide to the Papers of the University Librarian of the University of Virginia, ca. 1920-ca. 1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the University Librarian ca. 1920-ca. 1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-12/1/1.671
This collection consists of ca. 10,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Office of the University Librarian, Alderman Library, University of Virginia on 1997 July 25.
Scope and Content Information
Personal papers of Harry Clemons but containing considerable quantities of official materal.
Contains material relating to Clemons's history of the University of Virginia Library ( The University of Virginia Library, 1825-1950: story of a Jeffersonian foundation), including typescript versions of footnotes and bibliographical citations.
Collection contains a letter from Pearl Buck to Mrs. Clemons thanking her for congratulations on the Pulitzer Prize and commenting on the reception by reviewers of "The young revolutionist" which was written for young children of 12 to 14 "so that children in the churches might learn something about China without knowing it. to have it taken as a novel seems absurd...."
Organization
Series I: Papers of Harry Clemons, University Librarian Boxes. 1-16
Series II: History of UVa Library Project. Boxes 17-29
Contents List
- I: Papers of Harry Clemons
  - Ackert, E.G. 1928-1953 (Box 1)
  - Albemarle County Historical Society 1951-1960 (Box 1)
  - Alderman Library 1951-1958 (Box 1)
  - Alderman Library-Miss Land's Descriptions 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Alderman Library-Tours 1938-1954 (Box 1)
  - Alumni News 1952 (Box 1)
  - American Bible Society 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - American Geographical Society 1931-1950 (Box 1)
  - American Library Association 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society 1950 (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross 1960 (Box 1)
  - Association of College and Reference Librarians 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Ayer, Thomas Parker 1954 (Box 1)
  - Baker and Taylor 1927 (Box 1)
  - Barber, Abbie C. 1928 (Box 1)
  - Bates, M.S. 1927-1955 (Box 1)
  - Berea College 1932-1933 (Box 1)
  - Berkeley, Francis L., Jr. 1950-1960 (Box 1)
  - Berkin, John 1929 (Box 1)
  - Beville, Miss Katherine H. 1950-1957 (Box 1)
  - Bibliographical Society of the University of Virginia 1951-1958 (Box 1)
  - Bodleian Library, Oxford University 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Books left in Nanking n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bowen, A.J. 1926-1943 (Box 1)
  - Brede, Alexander 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - Brooke, C.F. Tucker 1927 (Box 1)
  - Brown, G.D. 1927-1954 (Box 2)
  - Browsing Room 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Buck, Pearl S. 1932 (Box 2)
  - Calloway, William C. 1928 (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Dwight D 1930-1955 (Box 2)
  - Cappon, Lester J. 1950-1958 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Public Library 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Public Library 1951-1957 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Public Library Manual 1953-1956 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Public Library Miscellaneous 1953-1956 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Public Library Book Committee 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville Chamber of Commerce 1931-1933 (Box 2)
  - Charlottesville School for Boys 1930-1934 (Box 2)
  - Chen Chang-wei 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Chen Chuen-Ho 1928 (Box 2)
  - Chen Tso-Kwei 1929 (Box 2)
  - Chen Yu-gwan 1936-1945 (Box 2)
  - Cherry, James D. 1950 (Box 2)
  - Children's Home Society of Virginia 1931-1934 (Box 2)
  - China Missions 1951-1957 (Box 2)
  - China Weekly Review 1927 (Box 2)
  - Civic League of Charlottesville and Albemarle 1955-1960 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1955-1956 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1957 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1958 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1959 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1959 (Box 2)
  - Clemons, Harry 1954 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1953 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1952 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1948-1950 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1947-1948 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1946-1947 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1944-1945 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1943-1944 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - Clemons, Harry 1941-1942 (Box 3)
  - Cochran, Anne 1952-1954 (Box 4)
  - Cochran, Gwendolyn n.d. (Box 4)
  - Cochran, Samuel 1927-1933 (Box 4)
  - Cochran, William 1937 (Box 4)
  - Colonnade Club 1927-1957 (Box 4)
  - Colonnade Club-Tablet 1952 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry J.-Retirement Letters 1950 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Henry-Thomas Jefferson Award 1950-1960 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Henry J.-University of Virginia Memorials 1944-1946 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Henry J.-Venable School, Charlottesville School for Boys 1930-1931 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Retirement Notices 1930 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Fry and Jefferson Map - Letters 1950 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-List of Writings 1928-1957 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Publications 1939 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Publications 1939 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry 1940 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Cemetery 1940 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry-Fry & Jefferson Map n.d. (Box 4)
  - Columbia University 1927 (Box 5)
  - Column Club-Psi Upsilon 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Commercial Press 1928 (Box 5)
  - Cottrell and Leonard 1934 (Box 5)
  - Craig, Hardin 1937-1960 (Box 5)
  - Craig, Hardin, Jr. 1953 (Box 5)
  - Craighill, Lloyd 1938 (Box 5)
  - Croll, Morris W. 1951 (Box 5)
  - Cudlip, William J. 1951 (Box 5)
  - Dalton, Jack 1956-1959 (Box 5)
  - Darden, President and Mrs. n.d. (Box 5)
  - Davis, Elmer n.d. (Box 5)
  - Davis, John K. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Davis, Roswell n.d. (Box 5)
  - Denniston, Louis N. 1950-1951 (Box 5)
  - Dickinson College 1927 (Box 5)
  - Dieterich, F.W. n.d. (Box 5)
  - Djantz, Fantz 1927 (Box 5)
  - Dodds, Solon A. 1955 (Box 5)
  - Dunnington, F.P. n.d. (Box 5)
  - Dutcher, George M. 1929-1930 (Box 5)
  - Elliot, Mrs. Edward 1945-1949 (Box 5)
  - Emeriti Census 1955-1959 (Box 5)
  - Episcopal High School 1932-1960 (Box 5)
  - Farmington Country Club 1954 (Box 5)
  - Federal Council of Churches 1931 (Box 5)
  - Fischbach, John H. 1958 (Box 5)
  - Fisk University 1927 (Box 5)
  - Fredericks, Marshall n.d. (Box 5)
  - Garden Club of Virginia-Tablet 1952 (Box 5)
  - Garden Week 1952 (Box 5)
  - Garside, B.A. 1928 (Box 5)
  - Gentry, Fenton 1934 (Box 5)
  - Gibson, Robert F. 1939 (Box 5)
  - Gillett, P.L. 1928-1929 (Box 5)
  - Geriffing, J.E. 1929 (Box 5)
  - Grolier Society, Book of Knowledge 1928-1929 (Box 5)
  - Hall, Franklin N.-Taxi Driver 1950 (Box 5)
  - Hamilton, C.H. 1927-1931 (Box 5)
  - Harper, Mr. and Mrs. George McLean 1959 (Box 5)
  - Harper, Isabel 1933 (Box 5)
  - Hartford Public High School 1927 (Box 5)
  - Hill, Frank P. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Hillcrest 1929 (Box 5)
  - Holgate, T.F. n.d. (Box 5)
  - Houghton, Herbert 1951 (Box 5)
  - Howland, L.A. 1929-1931 (Box 5)
  - Hsu, Chen 1931 (Box 5)
  - Hudson, F.B. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Hughan, Miss E.W. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Hutchison, A.C. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Hwang Hsi-Chen 1927 (Box 5)
  - Illick, J.T. 1928 (Box 5)
  - India 1953 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Public Affairs 1951 (Box 5)
  - James, W.J. 1927-1940 (Box 5)
  - Jenkins, Emily n.d. (Box 5)
  - Jenkins, Mrs. H.C. 1933 (Box 5)
  - Jenkins, Mary Hale 1935-1956 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, James G. 1956-1958 (Box 5)
  - Johnson, Nelson T. 1927-1947 (Box 5)
  - Kingsley, James Morse, Jr. 1937-1956 (Box 5)
  - Koch, T.W. 1927 (Box 5)
  - Kuling House 1928-1929 (Box 5)
  - Kung Tsen 1928 (Box 5)
  - Kuo, T.S. 1927-1929 (Box 5)
  - Lancaster, H. Carrington 1954-1959 (Box 5)
  - Land, Roy 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Lerman, Mary and Tsai, Christiana 1953 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Edmund J. 1939 (Box 6)
  - LeGrand, Mrs. Wyatt A. 1952-1956 (Box 6)
  - Li Siao-yuen 1927-1942 (Box 6)
  - Libraries 1930 (Box 6)
  - Library Journal 1927-1945 (Box 6)
  - Library of Congress 1927-1959 (Box 6)
  - Liu Kwoh-chuin 1927-1947 (Box 6)
  - Lobenstein, E.C. 1930 (Box 6)
  - Lomb Optical Collection 1955 (Box 6)
  - Loos, George W., Jr. 1928 (Box 6)
  - Love, H.H. 1927-1940 (Box 6)
  - Lowdermilk, W.C. 1936-1946 (Box 6)
  - McClure, Wallace 1955 (Box 6)
  - McCue, E.O., Jr. 1933 (Box 6)
  - McElroy, Robert 1938-1959 (Box 6)
  - McGee, Elsie 1955-1959 (Box 6)
  - McFarlane, W.H. 1953-1959 (Box 6)
  - McIntire, Paul G. 1928-1950 (Box 6)
  - McIntire Concerts 1929 (Box 6)
  - Macpherson, Oscar 1931 (Box 6)
  - Madison Hall 1928-1960 (Box 6)
  - Malone, Dumas 1959 (Box 6)
  - Ma Wen-Hwan 1929-1930 (Box 6)
  - Miller, William M. 1955 (Box 6)
  - Miller, Floyd J. 1941 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. Sarah Matthews 1956 (Box 6)
  - Myers, C.H. 1927-1932 (Box 6)
  - Mystical Seven 1928-1960 (Box 6)
  - Mills, Samuel J. 1928-1954 (Box 6)
  - Moffet, Anna E. 1927 (Box 6)
  - Murphey, William R. 1935 (Box 6)
  - Myers, H.H.B. 1927 (Box 6)
  - Mystic Stamp Program 1932-1933 (Box 6)
  - Nanking Foreign residents, March 1527 1927 (Box 6)
  - Nanking, Notes On 1927 (Box 6)
  - Nanking Library, University of - Receipts 1929-1935 (Box 6)
  - Nanking Library, University of 1927-1930 (Box 6)
  - Nanking, University of 1929-1957 (Box 7)
  - Newcomb, John Lloyd n.d. (Box 7)
  - National Geographic Society n.d. (Box 7)
  - New York Times 1929-1936 (Box 7)
  - New Orleans 1930 (Box 7)
  - Nicolson, F.W. 1931 (Box 7)
  - North Chinese Herald 1928 (Box 7)
  - Orientalia 1929 (Box 7)
  - Osgood, Charles Grosvenor 1929-1943 (Box 7)
  - Owen, L.J. 1929-1931 (Box 7)
  - Oxford University 1960 (Box 7)
  - Parrott, T.M. 1928-1940 (Box 7)
  - Parrott, T.M. Bibliography 1935 (Box 7)
  - Parrott, T.M. Bibliography - Correspondence 1934-1935 (Box 7)
  - Pavilions 1952-1959 (Box 7)
  - Paxton, J. Hall 1927-1929 (Box 7)
  - Periodical Subscriptions 1937-1960 (Box 7)
  - Perrin, M.L. 1928 (Box 7)
  - Perry, Everett R. 1927 (Box 7)
  - Peyton, Bradley, III 1957 (Box 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1929-1958 (Box 7)
  - Plaques 1956-1959 (Box 7)
  - Porter, Howard 1927 (Box 7)
  - Presbyterian Church 1931-1935 (Box 7)
  - Presbyterian Mission Board 1929-1932 (Box 7)
  - Price, Carl Fowler 1932-1947 (Box 7)
  - Price, Philip Frances (father) and Frank W. (son) 1928-1960 (Box 7)
  - Princeton University 1951-1959 (Box 8)
  - Psi Upsilon 1933-1959 (Box 8)
  - Priest, Ellie M. 1927-1934 (Box 8)
  - Purcell, Miss M.H. 1928 (Box 8)
  - Quenzel, Carrol H. 1960 (Box 8)
  - Rader, Norval and Mary 1954 (Box 8)
  - Raven Society July 1940 - 1940-1948 (Box 8)
  - Raven Society until July 1940 1931-1940 (Box 8)
  - Reisner, J.H. 1927-1950 (Box 8)
  - Retirement 1952 (Box 8)
  - Rice, Elwood E. 1930 (Box 8)
  - Robertson, A. Willis 1954 (Box 8)
  - Robson, Horace G. 1927 (Box 8)
  - Root, Logan H. 1928-1933 (Box 8)
  - Root, Robert K. 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - Sarvis, Guy W. 1930-1938 (Box 8)
  - Savage, Louise 1955 (Box 8)
  - Say, Georges 1927 (Box 8)
  - Scott, George T. 1927 (Box 8)
  - Shen Hsioh-chi 1930 (Box 8)
  - Shannon, Edgar Finley, Jr. 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Silvester, C.F. 1927 (Box 8)
  - Small, Alexander G. 1958 (Box 9)
  - Smith, Downing L. 1951 (Box 9)
  - Smith, George and Lucy 1928-1948 (Box 9)
  - Smith, Mrs. Herbert Makeldon 1952 (Box 9)
  - Smith, H.S.S. 1934 (Box 9)
  - Southeastern Library Association 1951 (Box 9)
  - S.P.C.A. 1958 (Box 9)
  - Speer, R.E. 1927-1937 (Box 9)
  - Speers, James M., Mr. 1930 (Box 9)
  - State Department 1929-1930 (Box 9)
  - Stewart, Albert N. 1927 (Box 9)
  - Stewart, Donald 1933-1941 (Box 9)
  - Stuart, John Leighton 1942 (Box 9)
  - Stuart, Warren H. 1927-1951 (Box 9)
  - Stewart, William R. 1928 (Box 9)
  - Stezer, Mary Evelyn n.d. (Box 9)
  - Swineford, Oscar, Jr. 1954-1958 (Box 9)
  - Swingle, W.T. 1927-1957 (Box 9)
  - Tai Am-Pang 1929 (Box 9)
  - Talks n.d. (Box 9)
  - Thomson, J. Claude 1928 (Box 9)
  - Tsao, Tsu-Ping 1930 (Box 9)
  - Tsu, K.M. 1930-1931 (Box 9)
  - United States Department of Agriculture 1927 (Box 9)
  - Wheeler, W. Reginald 1927-1946 (Box 9)
  - Whitehead, Mrs. R.H. 1928-1929 (Box 9)
  - Who's Who in America 1928-1958 (Box 9)
  - Who's Who in Library Service 1955-1956 (Box 9)
  - Williamson, C.C. 1927 (Box 9)
  - Wilson, H.W. Company 1927-1950 (Box 9)
  - Woods, Samuel B. 1931-1947 (Box 9)
  - Yale University 1930-1931 (Box 9)
  - Yu Pao-Shu 1928 (Box 9)
  - Taylor, Henry N. 1951 (Box 9)
  - Tufts College 1927 (Box 9)
  - Van Benschoten, Frieda 1927 (Box 9)
  - Van Hoesen, H.B. 1927-1936 (Box 9)
  - Van Hyning, Conrad 1951-1957 (Box 9)
  - University of Virginia 1927-1960 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1928-1936 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Education Association 1936 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Historical Society 1957-1960 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1929-1934 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Library Association 1951-1957 (Box 9)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1950 (Box 9)
  - Wade, Frank B. 1927 (Box 9)
  - Wan Kwoh-Ting 1929 (Box 9)
  - Wang, I-Ting 1927-1947 (Box 9)
  - Washington, George 1783 (Box 9)
  - Watson, Raymond W. 1941 (Box 9)
  - Wead, Katherine H. 1927-1956 (Box 9)
  - Webb Gift Committee 1952 (Box 10)
  - Wesleyan University 1927-1960 (Box 10)
  - Wesleyan University-Class of 1902 1952-1960 (Box 10)
  - Westcott, J.H. 1934 (Box 10)
  - Westminster Church 1954-1960 (Box 10)
  - Williams, J.E. 1927-1958 (Box 10)
  - Willis, Bailey 1927 (Box 10)
  - Wilson, W.F. 1929 (Box 10)
  - Wood, J.B. and W.H. 1929-1931 (Box 10)
  - Wu Kwan-Tsing 1930-1939 (Box 10)
  - Wyllie, John Cook n.d. (Box 10)
  - Zamsky Studio 1936 (Box 10)
  - Building General Information n.d. (Box 10)
  - Bookplates n.d. (Box 10)
  - Library Report 1950 1950 (Box 10)
  - Size of Collections 1944-1959 (Box 10)
  - Staff 1943-1956 (Box 10)
  - Publications n.d. (Box 10)
  - Expenditures 1949-1957 (Box 10)
  - Statistics 1948-1959 (Box 10)
  - Endowment 1926-1951 (Box 10)
  - The Home Library of the Garnetts of "Elmwood" 1957 (Box 11)
  - The Home Library of the Garnetts of "Elmwood," distribution of copies 1957 (Box 11)
  - The Home Library of the Garnetts of "Elmwood"-Reviews 1957 (Box 11)
  - Notes on Names - Correspondences 1960 (Box 11)
  - Interlaken Mills 1957 (Box 11)
  - Mott, Frank Luther, A History of American Magazines, Review 1957 (Box 11)
  - Richmond County Committee of Safety 1957-1959 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Magazine of History and Biography-Article Revised Version n.d. (Box 11)
  - Woodrow Wilson-Biographical Sketch in the Greatness of Woodrow Wilson 1955-1956 (Box 11)
  - The Virginia Librarian 1955-1957 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Magazine of History and Biography - Letters 1954-1958 (Box 11)
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation, Inc. 1956 (Box 11)
  - Woodrow Wilson Centennial Birthplace Restoration Fund 1956 (Box 11)
  - Woodrow Wilson Centennial Commission 1955-1956 (Box 11)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation 1956-1960 (Box 11)
  - Austin Gift Records 1888-1929 (Box 11)
  - Daily Readings 1948-1957 (Box 11)
  - Notes on Names at the University of Virginia n.d. (Box 12)
  - Notes on the Professors for whom the University of Virginia Halls and Residence Houses were named n.d. (Box 12)
  - Hulbert, Mrs. Henry S. n.d. (Box 12)
  - Annual Report-John Carter Brown Library 1958-1959 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notepads n.d. (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Papers Regarding: University of Nanking (loose papers), and (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Printed, including: (Box 13)
  - ALA Bulletin (Box 13)
  - The Commonwealth (Box 13)
  - The University of Nanking (Box 13)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News (Box 13)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 13)
  - The Wesleyan University Alumnus (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous papers, including material on: the Alderman Library Portrait list and Carter Class (foldered, not labeled), and (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous printed, including: (Box 14)
  - The A.L.A. in Siberia, Letters Written by Harry Clemons, Representative of the Amerian Library Association War Service, with the A.E.F. in Siberia 1919 (Box 14)
  - The Alderman Library at the University of Virgnia (Box 14)
  - The Cavalier Daily (Box 14)
  - College and Research Libraries (Box 14)
  - The Commonwealth (Box 14)
  - University of Virginia Alumni News (Box 14)
  - University of Virginia Newsletter (Box 14)
  - The Virginia Librarian (Box 14)
  - Virginia Library Bulletin (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous small items including: notes, pocket prayer books, and an address book, and (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous printed, including: (Box 15)
  - ALA Bulletin (Box 15)
  - University of Virginia Alumni Fund, Annual Report 1955 (Box 15)
  - "Diary for Five Years" (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Papers regarding: (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, (non-foldered, in original envelopes) (Box 16)
  - Original Copy of "Notes on UVa Professors for whom the Halls & Residence Houses are Named" (Box 16)
  - Tunghai University Library (Box 16)
  - Mrs. Frederick Haviland Burgevin, and (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Printed including: (Box 16)
  - The Cavalier Daily (Box 16)
  - The Daily Princetonian, and other Princeton printed matter (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Catalogs (Box 16)
- II: History of the University of Virginia Library Project
  - Card Catalogs (Unidentified) (Box 17)
  - Manuscript of History of UVa Library (Box 18)
  - Manuscript of History of UVa Library (Box 19)
  - Various Diaries (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Index Cards (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Index Cards (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Index Cards-(UVa Research Project) (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous items including: (Box 23)
  - Index Cards (Box 23)
  - Mrs. Gertrude Clayton File (Box 23)
  - Post Cards (Box 23)
  - Portraits (Box 23)
  - Mrs. Gertrude Clayton File (Box 23)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Notices and Reviews-Newspapers (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Notices and Reviews-Periodicals (Box 24)
  - Staff Copies (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Acknowledgements (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Announcements (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Binding (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Colophon (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Contents (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Corrections (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Distribution of Copies (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Footnote (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Forward (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Illustrations (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Index to Printed Copy (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Index to Typed Copy (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Title Page and Dedication (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section I-Text-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section I-Notes-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section II-Text-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section II-Notes-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section III-Text-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section III-Notes-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section IV-Text-Manuscript (Box 24)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section IV-Notes-Manuscript (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Text-Manuscript (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Notes-Manuscript (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on Librarians, General (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on John Vaughan Kean (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on William Werlenbaker (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on William Henry Brockenbough (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on Thomas Beverley Holcombe (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on Robert Riddick Prentis (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on William Aylett Winston (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on James Biscoe Baker (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on Frederick Winslow Page (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section V-Material on John Shelton Patton (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section VI-Text-Manuscript (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Section VI-Notes-Manuscript (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Notes, Supplementary-Gift Funds (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Notes, Supplementary-Lee Papers (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Notes, Supplementary-Dancing in the Rotunda (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Correspondence with Dr. Dumas Malone (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Letters to McGregor Fund Trustees-Remville Wheat (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Miscellaneous Notes (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Revisions Suggested (Box 25)
  - Clemons, Harry-History Project-Appraisals of Collections (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Notepads and Manuscripts-History Project (Box 26)
  - History Project Proofs (Box 27)
  - Index Cards-Index of Clemons' History (Box 28)
  - Letters received by H. Clemons re: his book, (not foldered, in original envelopes) (Box 29)